Fabian Rensing

Computer Science Master Student work@frensing.de

希 frensing.de | 🞧 frensing | 🛅 Fabian Rensing



Currently

Computer science master student at University of Helsinki.

About

As a student of computer science, I am dedicated to find innovative solutions and work on technologies that simplify life. Working in a team with people from various backgrounds is important to me, as the best progress can only come from diverse collaboration. My experience ranges from working in companies and research groups to organizing holiday camps for children. In my studies and work I excell in analytical problemsolving thinking and being able to explain complex concepts both in technical and simplified terms.

Education

M.S., Computer Science University of Helsinki

Sep 2022 - now

- GPA 4.82, Expected Graduation in May 2024
- Software Track

Erasmus Exchange Semester University of Helsinki Aug 2020 - Dec 2020 **B.S., Computer Science** Paderborn University Oct 2018 - Aug 2022

- GPA 1.7 (German scale)
- Business informatics minor

Experience

Research Assistant Empirical Software Engineering (UH)May 2023 - May 2024

- Fulltime position
- Setup of internal ML model pipelines and supporting infrastructure for EU project Vessel-Al
- Research vessel fouling estimation and hull cleaning detection from on-board sensor data

Student Staff Data Science Group (DICE)

Aug 2022 - Oct 2022

- Continuing development of open-source benchmark platform BASILISK
- Design and implement rework of core functionality for opensource benchmark framework IGUANA

Student Staff Fraunhofer IEM

Mar 2021 - Aug 2022

- Feature development for open-source IdP KeyRock, design of corporate design and deployment and configuration of internal test instance
- Setup and configuration of Jupyter Hub instance using Docker and Kubernetes for internal use by colleagues

Tutor Data Structures and Algorithms Course at UPB Apr 2020 - Jul 2020

• Teaching weekly classes, explaining exercises, solving student understanding problems

Student Staff viadee Unternehmensberatung AG Sep 2018 - Mar 2019

 Analysing client domain and development of testing routines for client in the financial sector

IT Consultant viadee Unternehmensberatung AG Feb 2018 - Aug 2018

Sep 2015 - Jan 2018

2020

 Conception, development and testing of a work time planning software for a client in the telecommunication sector

IT Specialist for Application Development

 Shortened apprenticeship because of outstanding Grades, Deutsche Telekom AG

- Development of internal reporting website visualizing important key figures for the management of the department.
- Data aggregation and presentation from different data sources and colleagues for various requests and presentations

Awards Heinz-Nixdorf Elite Program Member Paderborn University

• Computer Science Faculty, Paderborn, Germany

Skills Problem solver, Critical thinking

- quick comprehension and familiarization in new subject domains
- being able to explain concepts on technical level, but also in simplified terms

Languages

- German Native Language
- **English** C1, Toefl iBT score 111/120 (18.12.2021)
- Finnish A1.1

Technical Skills

- Java, Spring (Boot), Clean Code, Gradle, Maven
- Python, Django
- Javascript, Node.js, React
- SQL, mostly worked with ORACLE SQL
- MongoDB
- Git, GitHub, collaborating in Teams
- Docker, Docker Compose
- Experience with Kubernetes, Azure, AWS
- HTML, CSS
- Learning **Haskell** at the moment

• Citizenship: German

Residence: Helsinki, Finland

Interests • Bouldering, cycling, reading, listening and collecting music

· Building and flying racing drones

Volunteering Organization and team leading at local holiday camp for children 2014 - 2022

aged 10 - 15